

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211













Sr. IT Executive seeking roles in IT Project/Program Management, Software Development, Key Account Management, Vendor Management, Product Development with hands-on exposure to ML/DL/AWS technologies



Current Designation: Senior Delivery Manager

Total Experience: 20 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: John Deere

Highest Degree: Business Analytics [Business

Analytics]

Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: IT/Networking-Mgr

Industry: Industrial Products/Heavy Machinery

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Sr. IT Executive, Team Lead, IT Project Management, Software Development, Software Design, Requirement Gathering, Key Account Management, Vendor Management, Product Development, Business Analysis, KPI Analysis

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

# Summary

Accomplished leader, interested in suitable positions in your organization that involves solving customer problems using data and analytics, Software development and delivery, Production Support, Product and Process Management, Account Management & implementation of key initiatives. I have 20+ years of international experience (13 years in India + 8 years in US) in the Information Technology Industry including 10+ years' of experience in captive outsourcing, program and people management. Currently working as a Senior Delivery Manager, passionate about Software Engineering, Delivery & People Management and engineering products using Python, ML/AI & AWS. Recognized for inspiring team members to excel.

# Work Experience

- John Deere as Senior Delivery Manager Jul 2007 to Till Date
- \* Led an analytics initiative to model customer repayment behavior and through the model classified customers. This model helped to retain more than 1500+ good customers and drive topline performance.
- \* Developed resume clustering systems and automated the first level fitment of the sourced resumes and reduced the TAT for recruitment team by 75%.
- \* Combined data from Service Now and text from user feedback to perform anamoly detection. The work is still underway, so that an outage in the critical systems can be predicted.
- \* Automated responses using chatbot technologies to improve user satisfaction. This enabled the support team to shift focus towards high value activities. The subsequent load analysis has helped in determining traffic patterns.
- \* Engineered multiple IT applications from scratch and managed their lifecycle. Handled scrum teams and delivery of many mission critical applications. Responsible for Yearly performance review of employees and contract teams
- \* Led Regional Customer Acquisition IT program to create a robust project portfolio and developed application road map for the region. Managed cross-functional teams, in short, I was IT to business and business to IT
- \* I was the joint product owner for Dealer business systems and thus built a shared vision of those products across
- Performed key role in setting up Tier 1 help desk to support dealer operations.
- \* Trained, mentored and motivated employees for better employee connect.

#### Igate Mastech as Senior Consultant Jul 2006 to Jun 2007

- \* As a development lead, oversaw scope definition, iteration planning, prioritization, design, and reviews.
- \* Collaborated with other groups including business, quality-assurance and management staff to effectively manage tasks, defects, deliverables, scheduling, resources, priorities, and risks.
- \* Development and support of business rules using JRules.

#### Cognizant Technology Solutions as Senior Associate Jul 1998 to Jun 2006

\* Co-ordinated with business analysts, product managers and development managers to define scope and schedules and user acceptance testing.

# **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

- \* Managed a team of 20+ that included Developers, business analysts and architects
- \* Served as a liaison for big offshore teams, thus managed multiple successful product deliveries and critical patches
- \* Responsible for 24/7 production support
- \* Supported the Sales and Account Management teams in reviewing RFP's and contributed to product road maps decisions.
- \* Was instrumental in growing the 10 member team to more than 50+ members, on couple of occasions.

^ Back to Top

## Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Bharathidasan University, Trichy in 1996
PG: Business Analytics (Business Analytics), Part time from Indian School of Business (ISB), Hyderabad in 2018

^ Back to Top

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Project/Program Management	2020	14 Year(s)
Data & Analytics (ML/DL/AWS)	2020	4 Year(s)

^ Back to Top

## **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.